Register of the Raymond L. Bland papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Raymond L. Bland papers
1919-1941
68024
Hoover Institution Archives
4 manuscript boxes, 3 envelopes (2 linear feet)
Correspondence, reports, memoranda, financial records, and printed matter relating to the work of the American Relief Administration in Europe and Russia, 1919-1924, and the President's Committee on War Relief Agencies, 1941.
Bland, Raymond L.
Access
The collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items, computer media, and digital files. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos, films, or digital files during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual or digital material is immediately accessible.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Contents note
Correspondence, reports, memoranda, financial records, and printed matter relating to the work of the American Relief Administration in Europe and Russia, 1919-1924, and the President's Committee on War Relief Agencies, 1941.
American Relief Administration.; United States. President's Committee on War Relief Agencies.; International relief.; Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921--Civilian relief.; United States--Foreign relations.; World War, 1914-1918--Civilian relief.; World War, 1939-1945--Civilian relief.
- American Food in the World War and Reconstruction Period, by Frank M. Surface and Raymond L. Bland, undated (Box 1)
  - Copy of special edition
  - Literary note
  - Correspondence
  - Lists of subscribers
  - Statistical tables
- American Relief Administration, 1919-1924, undated
  - "A.R.A. on the Edge of Siberia," report of the UFA-Urals District, manuscript copy, 1921-1923
  - Final report of the work in Hungary written by members of the American Child Welfare Mission, 1920
  - Financial records of A.R.A. accounts, undated
  - Memo and cable regarding Russian relief, undated (Box 2)
  - Cable summarizing Hungarian political situation, undated
  - Report of the Danzig Port Mission, 1919-1922
  - Report of the European Children's Fund Mission to Poland, 1919-1922
  - Report of American medical and sanitary relief in Russian famine, A.R.A. Bulletin, 1921-1923
  - "A Sketch of the Child-Feeding Operations of the A.R.A. Mission to Czechoslovakia, 1919-1921"
  - Summary review of financial transactions of the A.R.A. for European relief activities, 1919 August - 1924 December
- Armistice between Russians and Estonians, copy of agreement, 1919
- Commission for Relief in Belgium, Inc. map showing world food imports and exports, 1938
- Hoover, Herbert C.
- Maps (Box 3)
- Miscellany
- Office of Production Management, "Statistical Summary of Defense Progress,", 1941
- President's Committee on War Relief Agencies, 1941
  Scope and Contents note
  Contains reports, memoranda, etc.
- U.S. Food Administration, enabling legislation and executive orders
- Photographs, undated
  - 81 photos of relief activities of the Commission for Relief in Belgium and the American Relief Administration in Europe and Russia (Envelope A)
    Includes photo of Herbert Hoover and the CRB staff at Rotterdam.
  - 44 photos of wartime scenes in Europe during World War I (Envelope B)
    Includes photo of Gen. Paul von Hindenburg.
  - 13 photos of personal and miscellaneous scenes (Envelope C)
- 3 medals and cigar piece (Box 4)